Hello, hello, good evening everyone. Hello, hello, it's been a long time. Hello, hello, I'm Xueli, and today I'm lucky to have our guest, Mr. Xiaoqianbao.
Welcome to watch this live broadcast. Thank you, everyone. And then we're going to hand over the microphone to Mr. Xiaoqianbao.
Mr. Xiaoqianbao, please briefly introduce yourself to everyone, and then we can start with the teacher's part.
Okay, I'm Xiaoqianbao, and then I've been on Bilibili Live recently. Those of you who are familiar with me should know that I'm not the first time I've come to MD to be an official guest.
And then, and then today I'm going to bring you this.
A set of a set of this costume that I've been doing live recently.
An explanation of a basic idea and how to make it out of this complex costume.
I'm going to share these two points with you today.
And then I'm going to show you a little bit of what I've been doing lately.
This thing MD file.
Well, this is MD.
The MD part.
This is the board part.
There are a lot of boards.
I haven't completely merged it all together yet.
That's too much.
It's too close.
If you merge it together, you can only do one.
Show.
One of the functions of inspection.
That's this.
This is the number of boards.
In fact, there is no way to do it.
Second calculation.
Well, the last time I came to the live broadcast room to be a guest, I still shared that.
Paris 4 plus spring shoes.
Uh, that.
The board of that pair of shoes.
Uh, in comparison,
compared to the current backpack,
there are still a lot of them.
Then because of my.
Uh, my friends who are familiar with me know that my.
The final output of the particle diameter is actually relatively low.
Generally, uh, the particle diameter.
Is.
Two or.
Or.
Or one.
So in the end, the entire MD file is very large.
Then the whole file is basically divided.
I will divide it into three parts to make.
Uh, this is the jacket part.
And the backpack part.
Uh, and finally there is this accessory part.
Uh, the accessory part is mainly.
Uh, hat.
Uh, scarf.
Uh, in fact, in the later period, these photos like this headset.
In fact, it is also in MD.
Some minor processing.
Uh, there are some.
Um, some of the things behind it, like this headband.
I treat all of these as accessories.
There are also some bandages on the headband.
And then finally I'm in.
Uh, divide.
After I finished it.
Uh, I will finally.
Um, combine it in the MD.
Uh, the whole.
Um, the entire character.
80% of it.
Basically, it's all done in MD.
And finally, it's like this.
If the final output.
It's almost the same effect.
Um, in fact, there is still a lower body.
But I can't make the lower body in time.
But put.
The upper body is finished.
Then I made a one-on-one.
I will also show you the gloves part.
Well, this file, let me show you this file first.
This file has seen my Bilibili video.
It should be more familiar.
I uploaded a full process of making this doll.
This has been.
This has basically been seen by everyone.
This is also one of the accessories.
One of the accessories.
Well, this is the gloves part.
The gloves part, because I was the whole of my character at that time.
Uh, this one.
IP positioning is to set it to this one.
Uh,
outdoor outdoor exercise.
Then in the winter.
This one.
The scene.
So gloves, I choose this kind of thick nature.
It's a little bit messy.
And finally, because of the gloves, I did it like this.
Just like this.
Uh, the advantage of doing this is that I can maximize it.
To ensure that it is this joint of the finger joint.
This one.
Uh, the feeling of this fold of the grip.
Uh, so that it will feel better on this side.
Uh, it's better than making it in the state of a pose.
The feeling of the gloves on this side is good, because Apple Apple will often slide down.
Uh, after sliding down, you need to keep pulling it up.
Uh, even if we make the friction a little bigger, uh, in the calculation process, uh, it will slide down if it moves.
I'm done at the end.
I'll put it in this B.
Make a simple connection.
Put it on top of it.
Uh, let's go back to the file just now.
Wait a minute.
Uh, finally get this whole body.
This one.
This effect.
And then I did this whole process for a long time.
Uh, the whole light MD part, plus the gloves just now.
There are still some.
There may be some small accessories that are still broken.
Uh, for example.
This one.
This doll.
Uh, the doll was made during the live broadcast.
And then there are some like these.
The axe rope.
The pull rope.
Uh, there are some.
Yeah.
I've done a lot of pull ropes.
And then these whole MD parts have been done for about three months.
Three.
More than three months.
And then I finished the whole MD part.
And then in the end, in the end, the effect I had in this B was like this.
Uh, I think this is very good.
I think this is very good.
A lot of people should have seen it.
Uh, wait a minute.
It's stuck.
Yeah, but it's stuck.
Yeah.
Uh, my positioning is still the kind of hyper-realistic item
but a little bit more like this color.
Um.
Don't want to make the entire equipment too old-fashioned.
This kind of detail is a little less
It's also the process of the scarf
The process of the hat
There are also some details about this kind of clothing
Most of the energy of this work is spent on this backpack
The backpack spent
A lot of energy
And then the process of the gloves
The process of the gloves
This jp file
This jp file is a bit too big
So it may be stuck when the scroll is displayed
If it's stuck, wait for me
Then this is
I'm in this
I did a little bit of the lower body in this, but the lower body is not very good.
It's just that I took some of the old things and I replaced them.
Oh, I haven't reached the highest level yet.
Wait a minute.
I'm going to raise these to the highest level.
And then the next thing is to deal with the backpack as quickly as possible.
It's more casual to deal with the sleeping bag.
So it's just a fold.
It's done.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Uh, when I was at that MD user conference, I just showed this cap.
This is probably a production idea,
and the rest of the parts like those accessories, hats,
pajamas, and the whole around suit,
I haven't finished it yet.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Some details on the backpack
You may need to be patient, because there are a lot of details on the backpack.
I may need to spend some time to show you the details.
The following accessories are still old tools, which are made of plastic dust.
I will show you the details of the backpack.
There are a lot of details on the backpack.
I will show you the details on the backpack.
This is a backpack.
There are 5.4 billion parts in total.
I will show you the details as soon as possible.
Let's start today's topic.
You may not be able to see it because there is too much space.
You may miss it when you sit.
Maybe there is a small gap here.
There is a gap here.
so I had to deal with it.
I can't see it clearly when I zoom in.
Basically,
that's how I handled it in ZBrush.
When I was doing the live stream,
many friends and friends asked me
how to maintain the authenticity of the costume.
This is the theme we need to talk about today.
How to ensure the authenticity of the complicated costume.
I call it the sense of wearability.
How to ensure the sense of wearability of the costume
to be more realistic, more realistic.
It's not like a shell.
It's like a shell.
It's on the body and then it's over.
In this kind of super-realistic costume,
the details are not the most important thing.
The overall costume is worn.
That's the most important thing.
It needs to have a very good feeling of being worn.
Like a backpack, you need to have a strong sense of weight.
It's really about carrying it around.
这种这种这种感觉你才能才能把它的整体的这个服装的这种那种你真的感觉才能把它做的做得更到位
那无论是上面的这些啊无论是上面这些小的挂件啊底下这些啊斧头这种这种配件啊是还是身上挂的一些东西啊它所产生的这种
这种负重感这种穿着感都是
都是非常真实的啊然后这样在这种前提下你做出来的模型作品它才能往显示这个方向去靠
嗯很多时候很多时候我们的作品也确实是用md制作出来的
啊但是呢做出来的那个褶皱啊都非常奇怪嗯褶皱呢奇怪吗其实也到也到能理解了因为很多时候褶皱奇怪
是由于呃质板的问题所所造成的但大部分人呃大部分人就是出的问题呢是整个服装的穿着感很奇怪
我们把裸模去掉的时候它不像是它不像是穿在身上的嗯它只像是在服在身上的就服装是没有任何的穿着感没有重力感啊这个是我们去制作嗯超写实类的服装
对
遇到最大的问题
然后要去扯这个扯这个这种这个这个这个超写实类服装这种穿着感的问题的话啊我们又需要
我们又需要把我之前md用户大会讲的一个东西要把它搬出来讲了我把这个东西放在一个
啊还是跟以前一样我们把它放在一个合适的角度角度上我先随便截这张图
先把它放着
嗯
我这里把上次的ppt的图又拿回来废物利用了一下
就是整个服装穿着感它是由力来决定的
嗯
我这里把上次的ppt的图又拿回来废物利用了一下
就是整个服装穿着感它是由力来决定的
嗯
In general, the five forces that have the greatest impact on clothing are the first three forces, the tension force, the cutting force, and the hardening force.
I have said before that we can ignore the gravity and friction forces in the software, because the gravity is fixed.
It is fixed to be negative 9800, which is the default, it should be the simulated earth gravity, negative 9800, such a value.
Sometimes it may be used to make costume or some more floating clothing, we will adjust the gravity.
But under normal circumstances, the gravity is generally unchanged.
There is also friction force.
Friction force is something.
It is.
It is divided into two places.
One is on the model, which is on the naked model, and the other is on the clothing fabric.
The friction force on the naked model and the friction force on the clothing fabric.
These two actually have a bit of a mutual effect.
But in general, it will not be adjusted.
Many people actually don't know how to use this friction force, how to adjust it.
So in general, we don't want to move it.
But in fact, when we go to make clothes, under the premise of the friction force and the reduction force fixed, the most important thing that actually affects the wear and tear of the whole costume is the gravity.
Many people, many people don't adjust the gravity, that is, they have never moved the gravity.
The gravity is default.
But the clothes made are floating.
It's all floating in the sky.
It doesn't feel like it's falling down.
It's like this.
I'll open my brush.
Wait a minute.
My brush.
Look at our normal clothes.
It's all very heavy.
This is the movement of the wrinkle.
The movement of the wrinkle.
Although it will be affected by this posture.
The posture is actually the force.
The reduction force is produced.
And then it will affect the change of this wrinkle.
But under this premise, it will always have a default value.
There will always be a default value.
The gravity.
The gravity is default.
It's always there.
So, so when we first went to do the costume.
The gravity of this factor is to be done first.
Here.
If the costume, whether it's an antique or a modern style of costume.
Whether it's a real costume or a stylized costume.
Or a two-dimensional costume.
The default value is missing.
No matter how much you do these things in front of you, it's actually useless.
When making costumes, this is the first one.
The gravity is the first one.
And then we need to consider the tension in the back.
And then we need to consider the reduction force and the reduction force in the back.
The reduction force and the reduction force are actually the same thing.
It's not the same thing.
It's a set of things.
There is a reduction force.
And then it will inevitably produce a reduction force.
So this is the step to make it in MD.
Or in virtual software.
To make this.
This is our kind of.
Our costume.
A lot of people will ignore this step.
It's the weight of this step.
The weight of this step.
In fact, it is also.
In fact, it is very important.
It is to determine whether your entire costume has this.
Ten-to-ten sense of wear.
Preliminary conditions.
And then under this prerequisite.
We are.
What are we doing?
We have styles to decide the fold.
Of course, I'll wait a minute.
And then we'll talk about it.
I'll just take this case.
To make a simple.
A simple example.
If the backpack.
If there is a sense of weight.
This place.
Oh, I'm sorry.
This is too big.
The backpack.
If there is a sense of weight.
Like this side.
The fold.
It's usually this kind of.
It's more.
It's lower.
The sense of weight.
The more the sense of weight.
The more the fold.
The direction of the fold.
The more.
The lower.
The lighter the sense of weight.
The fold.
The direction.
Just.
The more horizontal.
Just a tail.
A gold.
And then.
When we make it.
In our minds.
We need to put this.
This thing.
When we make it.
Make it.
Finally.
Lay.
Lay it down.
What's going to happen.
When it comes to this.
This feeling.
Then.
And then.
This.
According to his own.
Just.
The ultimate idea.
To put this.
The fold.
To adjust.
Then I did it here.
It's actually this light.
Slightly light.
That's relative.
Sometimes.
When we do this.
A lot of times.
Point.
On this side.
But.
它并不仅影响一块板片它并不仅影响一块板片
这个边我们再切回到这里
把这个放大一点
力的影响它是整体性的
它并不仅仅只影响到像这个侧面这单纯的一块
它所有东西其实都是受影响的
那整个的力都是这样子的一个方向
往下去去坠的
那包身受到影响以后
肩带这些位置相对应的也会受到影响
那肩带受到影响了以后
整个的背包受到这样子力的拉扯了以后
那羽绒服相对应的也会受到力的拉扯
所以我这些地方在高模当中去看的话
这些地方相对应的都会去做
做这种力的方向的
标识
把力的方向标识的非常的明确
所以我们去看这样子的模型的时候
无论是我之前的那个赛车服的这个模型
还是我现在在做的这个模型案例
对于力的方向
我是标识的非常的明确的
这样子去看它的时候
服装就非常强烈的重量感
那重量感
有了以后服装穿着感
自然也就有了
整个的服装的穿着在身上感觉
这个是第一步
你服装必须有重量感
再轻的服装
再轻的服装像
像那种尼龙的面料
用面料用轻薄尼龙面料
它很很轻就相较于什么棉料来说的话
已经算蛮轻的就再轻的面料
它都是有重量的
它都是要往下往下去挂的
只是悬挂的褶皱的服装
方向跟方式不一样而已
但是它都要有这样子的一个趋势
这个趋势表达要非常的明确
这样才能把服装最基础的穿着感给它制作出来
然后在这个基础上
我们就可以进行下一步了
哎
稍等啊
在这个基础上
我们就可以进行下一步
下一步就是
款式与褶皱
服装款式非常多
这个我在上一次参加大会的时候也说过
这服装款式很多很多很多成千上万种
现在有各种各样不一样的变化
然后款式有什么去决定
有有有剪裁去决定
那这个是正间秀的这个款式
那正间秀的款式嗯
大概做了很多嘛
就是肩膀肩线啊
袖拢这块刚好是在在肩点上的
然后这个是插肩秀的
插件秀是这样子的款式
就从
从正面啊
背面是一样的
是这样子斜插过来
这样这个是落肩秀的啊
落肩秀吗
就是肩线落到这个位置
肩线做了延展
延展到这里
我们就先看这三种不一样的袖子
正肩秀
正肩秀的这个褶皱呢
可以是看到是这样子的
是沿肩点进行这样一个发散的
然后他这个呢还是稍微宽松一点的正肩秀
有一些我们在去做游戏模型的时候原画画的时候呢
这个原画
画出来设计啊
可能是那种比较偏紧身的
比方说一个比较壮硕的壮硕的男人
他穿了一个比较紧身的这种
正肩秀的一个T恤
然后比较合身的
那很多时候他的褶皱是从腋下进行发散
这个是
正肩秀款式的衣服的一个一个特征
他从受力点开始发散
无论是从肩点
还从腋下
他都是从受力点开始发散
那插肩秀的
款式的这个这个褶皱特征特征是什么样
一般的插肩秀和落肩秀
只要是这两种
衣袖款式了
插肩秀可能还还还
还不是这个特征
落肩秀是一定是这个特征
就一只要是落肩秀
他衣服一定是宽宽宽大大的
因为一般落肩的话
我我鼠标是这个特征
我我鼠标随便画了
大家随便看一下
因为一般落肩的话
袖拢深都会比较深
我只画一半
这个点
这个点一般都会比较比较深
正常的这个袖拢的话
可能只正常袖拢的话
只需要到这就足够了
到这
然后落肩的话
他会做一个延展
他会把肩斜线做一个延展
延展到这
这样子
这样就会产生一个落肩的效果
那肩斜线延展了以后
肩斜线延展了以后
袖拢深度也会要做相应的延展
也就是这里
这个点也会要做相应的延展
袖拢深一般要往下移
袖拢深移动了以后
呃侧缝线也要做相应的延展
侧缝线是哪
侧缝线是这
那这样子一个
嗯
落肩秀的版片啊
就就正版
呃就前版片就已经就就变变出来了
然后这个是个落肩秀的
那落肩秀基于基于他这样的特征呢
所以他他不可能宽松啊
他不可能紧身
他一定是个宽松的
嗯
擦肩秀呢
虽然看现在这个是是个
是个宽松的吧
但不一定啊
有的时候呢
像那种运动品牌的像
呃迪卡龙的这些经常会有一些这种素干衣啊
他也是擦肩秀的
他是比较紧身的啊
擦肩秀是可以做成紧身的或者或者是宽松的啊
但我这里就以这种宽松的擦肩秀为例
然后我们可以看一下擦肩秀的这个肘咒的走向
嗯
从这里挂下来的
他是挂下来的
很很大很柔顺的这种肘咒挂下来的
并不会像这种地方产生这样子的肘咒
就是比较小的
就是要比比较细小的那种变化
腋下可能还会产生这样子的这种并不会
然后再看落肩秀的话
落肩秀是个非常明确的
U字形
非常明确的
非常明确的一个U字形
嗯
其实其实插肩也是有一些就是落肩秀的特性的
我等会说为什么这这款衣服呢
他是他是沿着肩点这样子挂下来的
其实这跟材料有关
因为这个材料太软了
好
然后基于这样子的特点
那后面的这些我们再大概的看一下
这个是连肩秀
就肩膀是连在一起的
就没有没有肩线
然后这个是蝙蝠秀
这个泡泡秀
不同的通过这几张图呢
其实就能就能知道就不同的
不同的秀型不同的款式
出现褶皱是不一样的
然后这个就是制作
服装真实穿着
穿着感的第二步
根据服装的版式不同
款式不同
剪裁不同
要做出符合该剪裁相应的褶皱
你不能说
你不能说我在
落肩秀的这个款式上面
我去做正肩秀的这个褶皱
然后在这里
在正肩秀的这个款式上面
我去做落肩秀褶皱
这个是经常会遇到问题
这个是很多很多同学经常制作时候会遇到问题
尤其是尤其是MD处理
可能只处理到30%或者40%
甚至更低20%的程度
然后就去把它转移到JB当中去雕刻
在雕刻过程中
经常会把这种褶皱给雕刻错了
这是超多超多的
我都遇到不知道有多少这样子的问题了
经常会把褶皱给雕刻错了
不同款式的衣服
这个是可以记一下
就是不同款式的衣服
它所能产生的褶皱是完全不一样的
这里其实也
这里的褶皱为什么不一样
其实又需要回扯到上面的力
这里就要讲一下剪切力跟剪硬力
其实不懂这个的话
其实可以去看一下
我之前MD用户大会去
关于讲这五种力的一个基础讲解
然后这边其实写在这了
然后今天这个是个比较高清的录下来
然后可以大概的去看一下
然后今天我就不一一去讲解这个
然后这个是
制作超写实服装
穿着感的第二步
一定要在第一步完全满足的情况下去制作第二步
这样子才能更好的去保证你的服装的真实感
然后这个是
这个是
然后一般
然后一般我这些
稍等我喝口水
然后一般我这些东西制作完毕以后
我就会去
就是这些大的
褶皱的这种状态
我确认完毕了
我已经
我已经在MD当中确认的
基本确认的差不多了
我一般会在MD当中制作到80%的
这种程度
然后
然后再去到
到JV当中进行一些
进一些微处理微调
然后这些
全部确认了以后
直接去JV去处理
处理它的细节就可以了
稍等我卡住了
那我看看
Okay, I thought it was automatically saved.
If you go to make it in here, it's actually
I'll explain it one by one later.
It's just like a round case, just one by one.
To disassemble and explain, it's just a round case.
When I went to make it, I went to choose to make this round case.
I chose a relatively thin one.
This kind of very thin nylon kind of fabric round case
Then based on the fabric characteristics of such a round case
Then the curse I created
It must be that kind of
It's more fine, it's more and smaller, and it doesn't produce that kind of
The thick, thick nylon creates that kind of big curse
The big curse will be less corresponding
Then there is more of this kind of fine curse
Just like MD, except you are like this
But when you go to make it, you still need to control the number of curses.
MD, it can make that kind of curse density
There are so many, so many
But when we go to do the beautification process
Still have to be corresponding to control it
The number of curses
If the number of curses is more to a certain extent
On the contrary, the authenticity will drop
Is to control this degree
Then the whole
The whole of the blotting
I, I probably hit it.
I'm under pressure.
I only hit two.
In fact, the hit is not very high
I to me
I am in the state of his melancholy
I, I thought when I was making it
Is I don't want him to make the same as a breadcloth
Uh, the breadcloth
Well, if you really look at it, I'll go to find a reference
The curse of the breadcloth can produce this kind of curse
In fact, there is not much
If you are too strong
The curse that can be produced will become less
I just gave him a little less pressure
I made it a little bit smaller.
Okay, and then the accessories on it,
when I went to make it,
I thought about it.
I want to have a real one.
I want to have a fur line,
a little bit of wool,
so you can see the fold of the costume made.
Accordingly, it's a little bit thicker,
and then the back of this back of this bag,
I actually also adjusted the light.
When I went to make the back of this bag,
I also thought about it,
and I also thought about a lot of versions.
In the end, I confirmed it to this version,
which is the blue fabric part on the front.
I want it,
I want it to fold
a little bit thicker,
and then the dark part on the side,
I want it to be a little bit thinner,
and then you can see me inside,
I put a naked film inside,
and then I put this texture of this object,
this kind of hard line,
I put it,
I put it out,
and then I expressed the feeling that the object was installed in this backpack,
but the whole backpack,
the overall trend of this backpack,
or according to what I said before,
then I was in this place before,
it's just that I've been pulling it down,
and then I gave it a more obvious one.
This kind of gravity,
this kind of direction,
and then the feeling of hanging these down on top,
in fact,
it's just that I look from the side,
the whole backpack,
it's not like this,
straight,
it's just that I'm standing here,
and I'm going to hide this,
because I made the backpack,
this,
um,
the backpack system,
so,
like this kind of backpack system,
it has a gap between the backpack and it has a gap between the backpack,
and then the gap is getting bigger and bigger,
so the gap is getting bigger and bigger,
and then the gap is getting smaller and smaller,
so why is there such a change,
because this change is generated by gravity,
because my backpack,
uh,
this place is,
is slanted,
I'm not doing very well here,
here,
uh,
but in this position,
I went to ZB to adjust it,
uh,
in fact,
in,
in MD,
it can also be adjusted,
and then I really think the MD content is too laggy,
I don't want to,
I don't want to do it,
according to the normal production,
this place is a adjustable,
uh,
adjustable shoulder bag carrying system,
so this place should be carried by the backpack,
like this place,
uh,
this direction,
there is a,
there is a pulling force,
there is a cutting force,
so it will pull the shoulder strap here,
pull it straight,
then this place is not doing very well,
that is,
I really didn't pull it straight,
this is a mistake,
I went to ZB to fix it,
and then,
and then because,
because of the gravity of this slanting function,
so,
so the upper half of the backpack,
it will be a little farther away from the uh,
carrying system,
and the lower half,
it is basically tightly attached,
tightly attached together,
so this way,
through this kind of,
this kind of detail processing,
you can better express the weight of the backpack,
not just the weight of the backpack,
not just through the fold,
but also through this kind of,
uh,
change between each part and part,
to show the weight of the entire backpack,
and many people have seen these,
that is, uh,
I think what you have done in general,
what you have done,
uh,
I,
I put these files together today,
but it's really stuck to me,
especially stuck,
uh,
and then,
and then I'm in,
uh,
after processing it in ZB,
usually my last step,
I, I will directly enter the K show with that,
uh,
with me before to say that,
um,
that Paris,
uh,
uh.
Uh,
I guess I went too far,
uh,
because the pixel isn't in one layer.
So,
uh,
I like this kind of thing,
but because this is just me now,
I finished it
with this.
This is a lighting test.
Generally, the gray film is poured in first.
Pour it in, I'll go a little bit.
Simply, I'll give it a light.
I usually have one light, just one top light.
Just one light is enough.
And then I usually pull this HDR a little bit lower.
0.3, sometimes pull it to 0.2, 0.1.
There are all of them.
If you want to show this kind of layer of clothing,
this kind of layer of shadow,
and then the shadow is heavier,
if the contrast is stronger,
one light is enough.
And then this one is a little bit,
a little bit of material.
Of course, it is also a white film material.
To do a simple test, this is.
And then here I did some,
um, let's treat it like an advertisement.
This kind of rendering method in the product image method is also a little bit, a little bit of a test.
Um, the one on the top is what I did two days ago, two days ago.
Um, this one and this one's rendering method just changed a little bit, which is this one.
I made it a real light source of a rendering test,
and then this side is a little bit.
It's a little bit of a style-oriented kind of this kind of video test.
Uh, this whole process of my class is basically like this.
And then what I'm sharing today, uh, is basically over,
and then I'll leave it to you.
Oh, okay, okay, uh, before the teacher leaves,
let's see if there are any friends,
any questions, uh,
because I just saw that there are little friends in the chat saying this, uh,
can you share the UI interface?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'll send it to my group later.
Uh, yeah, all right, uh,
the teacher's group number.
Do you want to tell everyone about the group number?
Oh, it's okay, just look at my B station homepage.
Oh, okay, okay.
You can go and follow the B station of Teacher Xiao Qiamao,
and then in the little cat B,
oh, the main place of Teacher Xiao Qiamao's B station,
You can see the way to add groups on the top of the page.
If you are interested in the teacher's content,
you can also pay attention to our Bilibili account,
the Bilibili account of Mr. Xiaoxianbao,
and the official Bilibili account of Marvelous Designer.
And before, at the user exchange conference,
Mr. Xiaoxianbao was also the last guest
to share very useful content with you.
Don't forget to review the video.
Okay.
Thank you, Mr. Xiaoxianbao.
Thank you, Mr. Xiaoxianbao, for sharing.
Oh, there is a comment.
How do you deal with the relationship between the backpack and the body?
Just keep some of the backpack accessories.
And then there must be something as a collage.
Whether you keep the accessories on the backpack
or keep the accessories on the clothes,
it's all the same.
As long as you keep one part as a collage,
as a collage that connects two places,
it's okay.
Another friend asks,
does Marvelous Designer still have to re-build the line
from the front to the back of the ZB?
If you need to re-build the line,
you can take a look at it.
In my Bilibili,
in the Bilibili article,
the racing suit before,
he wrote,
I wrote,
how to re-manage the three sides of MD,
and then turn to the four sides.
Of course, now that MD has been optimized,
the four sides can actually be used.
If you're not,
if you're not particularly forced,
basically that's enough.
Okay.
The teacher's Bilibili account is
I am your Xiaoxianbao.
Yes, you can find it by searching directly.
Thank you.
Let's thank Mr. Xiaoxianbao for sharing today.
Okay, next.
Okay, I'll leave it to you.
Okay, now I'm going to share with you some new features of Marvelous Designer 2020 version.
Introduction